<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
    xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>In Case You Missed It (Law)</title>
    <itunes:owner>
    <itunes:email>icymi@y-naught.com</itunes:email>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>ICYMI Law dot com</itunes:author>
    <itunes:summary>Discover the latest legal news and content in the fediverse with this experimental AI-summarized newscast, an algorithmicly-generated examination of your host's Mastodon timeline. It follows a bunch of lawyers, law profs, and the like so you don't have too. Get the highlights of the day's most important law-related events, including the most-shared links, SSRN papers, and more – all in the span of five minutes or less. Each show links back to original source material so you can keep the bot honest. Trust no one, esp. if they're actually not a someone. Did I mention this was an experiment? ;)</itunes:summary>
    <itunes:image href="https://icymilaw.org/images/icymi_cover_1400.png"/>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <itunes:category text="News"/>
    <link>https://icymilaw.org</link>
    <item>
      <title>In Case You Missed It (Law): 2022-12-24</title>
      <link>https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-24.html</link>
      <description>
        <content type="html">
          <![CDATA[Welcome to the news! U.S. lawmakers have left out an important proposal to make court records free and Twitter has removed a suicide prevention feature. And two conservative prosecutors have been nominated for vacancies on their states' highest courts. Stay tuned for more information on these stories! <a href=”https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-24.html”>View the Digest/Primary Sources</a>]]>
        </content>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2022-12-24_show.mp3"
                 type="audio/mpeg" length="250669"/>
      <itunes:duration>251</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2022-12-24_show.mp3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Case You Missed It (Law): 2022-12-23</title>
      <link>https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-23.html</link>
      <description>
        <content type="html">
          <![CDATA[Max here, bringing you the latest news! Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky made a strong plea to Congress for more support in the war against Russia. Brooklyn Law School is looking for an experienced leader for a civil litigation clinic, and Google's control of the digital ad industry is opening the door to a range of abuses and schemes. Stay tuned for more updates, and don't forget to keep it locked here for all the latest news. <a href=”https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-23.html”>View the Digest/Primary Sources</a>]]>
        </content>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2022-12-23_show.mp3"
                 type="audio/mpeg" length="272549"/>
      <itunes:duration>273</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2022-12-23_show.mp3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Case You Missed It (Law): 2022-12-22</title>
      <link>https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-22.html</link>
      <description>
        <content type="html">
          <![CDATA[Welcome to the future of social media – decentralized, open source platforms like Mastodon, ActivityPub, and Bluesky are gaining traction. Could a 'Gmail moment' be on the horizon? Meanwhile, President Biden is nominating six individuals for federal judgeships, and a guide is available to help hosts of Mastodon instances navigate the legal risks associated with hosting such a platform. Keep tuning in to find out more! <a href=”https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-22.html”>View the Digest/Primary Sources</a>]]>
        </content>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2022-12-22_show.mp3"
                 type="audio/mpeg" length="237275"/>
      <itunes:duration>237</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2022-12-22_show.mp3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Case You Missed It (Law): 2022-12-21</title>
      <link>https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-21.html</link>
      <description>
        <content type="html">
          <![CDATA[In this edition, we start with a story about Kelly Conlon, a lawyer denied entry to a show due to facial recognition technology. Next, we take a look at a paper exploring design patents, which has sparked a new wave of debate on US intellectual property policy. Finally, the January 6th Project examines the omissions in the select committee's summary of their upcoming report on the Capitol Insurrection—a report that goes out of its way to present failed law enforcement and intelligence agencies in a positive light. It's time to stay informed! <a href=”https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-21.html”>View the Digest/Primary Sources</a>]]>
        </content>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2022-12-21_show.mp3"
                 type="audio/mpeg" length="237849"/>
      <itunes:duration>238</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2022-12-21_show.mp3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Case You Missed It (Law): 2022-12-20</title>
      <link>https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-20.html</link>
      <description>
        <content type="html">
          <![CDATA[Welcome to today's news roundup. We start off with a story about the importance of representation in the judiciary. This follows the portrait ceremony of Judge Robert L. Wilkins, who was appointed to the U.S. Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit. We'll also look at how the COVID-19 pandemic has opened up opportunities for Americans with disabilities in the job market. Finally, we'll review the résumé of Rep.-elect George Santos (R-NY), which is being called into question. Be sure to stay tuned for all the details.  <a href=”https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-20.html”>View the Digest/Primary Sources</a>]]>
        </content>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2022-12-20_show.mp3"
                 type="audio/mpeg" length="245905"/>
      <itunes:duration>246</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2022-12-20_show.mp3</guid>
    </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
