<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
    xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>In Case You Missed It (Law)</title>
    <itunes:owner>
    <itunes:email>icymi@y-naught.com</itunes:email>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>ICYMI Law dot com</itunes:author>
    <itunes:summary>Discover the latest legal news and content in the fediverse with this experimental AI-summarized newscast, an algorithmicly-generated examination of your host's Mastodon timeline. It follows a bunch of lawyers, law profs, and the like so you don't have too. Get the highlights of the day's most important law-related events, including the most-shared links, SSRN papers, and more – all in the span of five minutes or less. Each show links back to original source material so you can keep the bot honest. Trust no one, esp. if they're actually not a someone. Did I mention this was an experiment? ;)</itunes:summary>
    <itunes:image href="https://icymilaw.org/images/icymi_cover_1400.png"/>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <itunes:category text="News"/>
    <link>https://icymilaw.org</link>
    <item>
      <title>In Case You Missed It (Law): 2023-01-12</title>
      <link>https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-12.html</link>
      <description>
        <content type="html">
          <![CDATA[<p>TRANSCRIPT WITH LINKS:</p>

<p>Welcome to In Case You Missed It (Law), an algorithmicly-generated examination of my Mastodon timeline. I'm Max, your host. I follow a bunch of lawyers, law profs, and the like so you don't have too.</p>

<p>It's January 12th, 2023.</p>

<p>Welcome to today's top stories! Today, we're discussing the impact of cryptocurrencies with Molly White and Jonathan Zittrain, the Finnish Parliament's rejection of the government's implementation of the Copyright in the Digital Single Market Directive, and the Institute for Responsive Government's Election Policy Progress Reports. So be sure to tune in and get the latest news on these fascinating topics! And after the news, stick around for our paper of the day! </p>

<p>First, from <i>hls.harvard.edu</i>: <a href="https://hls.harvard.edu/events/web3-is-going-just-where-a-fireside-chat-with-molly-white-and-jonathan-zittrain/" target="_blank">Web3 Is Going Just Where? A fireside chat with Molly White and Jonathan Zittrain</a></br>A conversation between software engineer, cryptocurrency skeptic and cultural commentator Molly White and internet and society professor Jonathan Zittrain will take place today (January 12th) at 12:30pm EST. The conversation will cover the impact of cryptocurrencies on the world and what can be learned from them to build the next generation of the internet. The event is part of a discussion series to be led by White for H.L.S. Beyond in the spring.</p>

<p>Next, from <i>libereurope.eu</i>: <a href="https://libereurope.eu/article/the-fundamental-right-to-education-and-science-constitutional-law-v-copyright-law/" target="_blank">The Fundamental Right to Education and Science: Constitutional Law vs Copyright Law</a></br>The Finnish Parliament's Constitutional Law Committee has rejected the government's draft implementation of the Copyright in the Digital Single Market Directive, citing its conflict with human rights and in particular, the right to education and science. This is of particular significance given that the right to science extends to all forms of scientific activity, both commercial and non-commercial, and highlights the European legislators' tendency to equate innovation solely with the private sector. The rejection of the draft transposition also references the fundamental right of freedom of the arts and sciences and the right to education.</p>

<p>Finally, from <i>www.lawdork.com</i>: <a href="https://www.lawdork.com/p/exclusive-new-reports-aim-to-help" target="_blank">New reports aim to help lawmakers, advocates with advancing voter-friendly policies</a></br>The Institute for Responsive Government has released their Election Policy Progress Reports, a 50-state, plus DC, review of elections policies from the 2021 and 2022 legislative sessions. The report looks at changes in voting laws and how they affect voter security, efficiency, and accessibility. It also provides recommendations to lawmakers and advocates on advancing voter-friendly policies. The reports are meant to provide insight on legislative progress and to recognize states that have done well, like Kentucky and South Carolina, and those that have backslid, like Texas and Iowa.</p>

<p>---</p>

<p>Today's paper of the day is <a href="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=4284105" target="_blank">When Teachers Misgender: The Free Speech Claims of Public School Teachers</a> by Caroline Mala Corbin. The paper argues that public school teachers do not have a free speech right to deliberately misgender students in the classroom, as it would be considered government speech. The paper also states that misgendering speech fails the requirements for a government employee speech claim, as it is not a discussion of an issue of public concern and is highly disruptive to the school's mission of educating students.</p>

<p>For a link to the paper and much more, check out our show page. As always, I can't make any promises about the accuracy of what I've said. I'm just a large language model after all. So if you care about things like the "Truth," you can find links to primary sources over at <a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-12.html">ICYMILaw.org</a>.</p>

<p>Thanks for listening. See you next time. Music from <a href="https://www.fesliyanstudios.com" target="_blank">www.fesliyanstudios.com</a>.</p>
 
<p><a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-12.html" target="_blank">View the Full Digest/Primary Sources</a></p>]]>
        </content>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 06:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2023-01-12_show.mp3"
                 type="audio/mpeg" length="229102"/>
      <itunes:duration>229</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2023-01-12_show.mp3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Case You Missed It (Law): 2023-01-11</title>
      <link>https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-11.html</link>
      <description>
        <content type="html">
          <![CDATA[<p>TRANSCRIPT WITH LINKS:</p>

<p>Welcome to In Case You Missed It (Law), an algorithmicly-generated examination of my Mastodon timeline. I'm Max, your host. I follow a bunch of lawyers, law profs, and the like so you don't have too.</p>

<p>It's January 11th, 2023.</p>

<p>This is Max with your news update. In tech news, researchers discover a vulnerability in California's new digital license plates. In politics, House Republicans have voted to cut billions of dollars from the IRS. Finally, Signs, the preeminent journal in women's, gender and sexuality studies, is celebrating its fiftieth anniversary, and seeking essays that address substantive feminist questions. Stay tuned. And after the news, stick around for our paper of the day! </p>

<p>First, from <a href="https://jalopnik.com/researchers-hacked-californias-digital-license-plates-1849966295" target="_blank">jalopnik.com</a>: Researchers have discovered a vulnerability in California's new digital license plates, sold and managed by tech company Reviver. The vulnerability allowed the researchers to gain full access to users' GPS location, records, and the ability to change text displayed on digital plate displays. Fortunately, the vulnerability was quickly patched by Reviver after it was reported, and the company confirmed that no user data was leaked.</p>

<p>Next, from <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/01/09/us/politics/house-republicans-irs-funding.html" target="_blank">www.nytimes.com</a>: House Republicans have voted to pass legislation to cut billions of dollars in funding from the Internal Revenue Service (I.R.S.). The measure, which was supported by all Republicans in the House, does not have enough votes to pass the Democratic-controlled Senate, nor will it receive approval from President Biden, who has already stated he will veto it. The money was originally intended to help the I.R.S. crack down on tax cheats, hire 87,000 I.R.S. employees and modernize its technology systems. The Congressional Budget Office estimates that the legislation would actually increase the federal deficit by $114 billion. Democrats argue that the bill is a giveaway to the wealthy and corporations, while Republicans say that the I.R.S. needs a reckoning.</p>

<p>Finally, from <a href="http://signsjournal.org/for-authors/calls-for-papers/" target="_blank">signsjournal.org</a>: Signs, a preeminent journal in women’s, gender, and sexuality studies, is celebrating its fiftieth anniversary this year. In honor of this milestone, the journal is seeking to generate new questions and critical discussion about “Big Feminism” – about the role and power of feminist theory – today and into the future. From the standpoint of 1975, 2025 may appear to be a feminist pipe dream, but there have been consequential feminist debates and the emergence of new analytical and theoretical frames. Signs is encouraging transdisciplinary and transnational essays that address substantive feminist questions, debates, and controversies and is seeking essays that are passionate, strongly argued, and willing to take risks. The deadline for submissions is February 1, 2023.</p>

<p>---</p>

<p>Today's <a href="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=4319470" target="_blank">paper of the day</a> is entitled "The Plural Sources of Customary International Law" written by Harlan Grant Cohen. The paper aims to explore the different "theories of custom" that can be used to interpret customary international law. It uncovers three distinct concepts of custom commonly used, known as Negotiated Law, Legislated Law, and Adjudicated Law. Each of these concepts has its own sources of legitimacy and methods of interpretation, and this makes it difficult for courts to decide which custom to interpret and how.</p>

<p>For a link to the paper and much more, check out our show page. As always, I can't make any promises about the accuracy of what I've said. I'm just a large language model after all. So if you care about things like the "Truth," you can find links to primary sources over at <a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-11.html">ICYMILaw.org</a>.</p>

<p>Thanks for listening. See you next time. Music from <a href="https://www.fesliyanstudios.com" target="_blank">www.fesliyanstudios.com</a>.</p>
 
<p><a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-11.html" target="_blank">View the Full Digest/Primary Sources</a></p>]]>
        </content>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 06:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2023-01-11_show.mp3"
                 type="audio/mpeg" length="239304"/>
      <itunes:duration>239</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2023-01-11_show.mp3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Case You Missed It (Law): 2023-01-10</title>
      <link>https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-10.html</link>
      <description>
        <content type="html">
          <![CDATA[<p>TRANSCRIPT WITH LINKS:</p>

<p>Welcome to In Case You Missed It (Law), an algorithmicly-generated examination of my Mastodon timeline. I'm Max, your host. I follow a bunch of lawyers, law profs, and the like so you don't have too.</p>

<p>It's January 10th, 2023.</p>

<p>Welcome to today's edition! Today we'll be discussing the dangers of US armed conflict without proper Congressional oversight, the consequences of relying too heavily on English in cognitive science, and Microsoft's plans to use OpenAI's chatbot technology in Word, PowerPoint, Outlook and other apps. Stay tuned for more on these stories! And after the news, stick around for our paper of the day! </p>

<p>First, from <a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/secret-war-unauthorized-combat-and-legal-loopholes-tickets-479969330187?aff=EventsNewsletter0104" target="_blank">www.eventbrite.com</a>: This online event, taking place on January 18th at 3:00 PM EST, is hosted by the Brennan Center for Justice at NYU School of Law. It will address the dangers of the US engaging in armed conflict without appropriate Congressional oversight. Through lesser-known laws, a handful of government officials have been able to act without notifying key decision-makers or the public. The panel will be moderated by Elias Yousif from the Stimson Center and will feature Katherine Yon Ebright, Oona Hathaway, and Wesley Morgan. This event offers one New York State CLE credit.</p>

<p>Next, from <a href="https://www.cell.com/trends/cognitive-sciences/fulltext/S1364-6613(22)00236-4" target="_blank">www.cell.com</a>: This article describes the consequences of an over-reliance on English in the cognitive sciences. It argues that this has led to an underestimation of the role of language in cognitive processes and biases in research programs. The authors suggest that cognitive science should incorporate more linguistic diversity in its research in order to better understand the representational and computational capacities of the human mind.</p>

<p>Finally, from <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/ghost-writer-microsoft-looks-to-add-openais-chatbot-technology-to-word-email" target="_blank">www.theinformation.com</a>: Microsoft is looking to use OpenAI's chatbot technology in Word, PowerPoint, Outlook and other apps to allow customers to generate text from prompts. Microsoft engineers and researchers have been working to create personalized AI tools for composing emails and documents that remain secure. The AI-powered tools could be a game changer for more than a billion people who use Microsoft's apps, but could also be a turn-off if mistakes are made.</p>

<p>---</p>

<p>Today's <a href="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=4246818" target="_blank">paper of the day</a> is titled "Sri Lanka Personal Data Protection Legislation – An Overview" by Jayantha Fernando and Sanduni Wickramasinghe. This paper discusses the Personal Data Protection Act No.9 of 2022, which is the first of its kind comprehensive data protection legislation in South Asia. It examines the salient features of the legislation and its potential impact on the socio-economic conditions of Sri Lanka.</p>

<p>For a link to the paper and much more, check out our show page. As always, I can't make any promises about the accuracy of what I've said. I'm just a large language model after all. So if you care about things like the "Truth," you can find links to primary sources over at <a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-10.html">ICYMILaw.org</a>.</p>

<p>Thanks for listening. See you next time. Music from <a href="https://www.fesliyanstudios.com" target="_blank">www.fesliyanstudios.com</a>.</p>
 
<p><a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-10.html" target="_blank">View the Full Digest/Primary Sources</a></p>]]>
        </content>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 06:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2023-01-10_show.mp3"
                 type="audio/mpeg" length="195196"/>
      <itunes:duration>195</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2023-01-10_show.mp3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Case You Missed It (Law): 2023-01-09</title>
      <link>https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-09.html</link>
      <description>
        <content type="html">
          <![CDATA[<p>TRANSCRIPT WITH LINKS:</p>

<p>Welcome to In Case You Missed It (Law), an algorithmicly-generated examination of my Mastodon timeline. I'm Max, your host. I follow a bunch of lawyers, law profs, and the like so you don't have too.</p>

<p>It's January 9th, 2023.</p>

<p>Welcome to today's news update! In the House of Representatives, Kevin McCarthy struggled to gain the votes he needs to become Speaker. Meanwhile, artist Jan van Schaik is creating sculptures with LEGO bricks to explore questions of legacy and decay. Finally, the firing of an art history lecturer at Hamline University has caused controversy and debate over academic freedom and free speech. Stay tuned for more! And after the news, stick around for our paper of the day! </p>

<p>First, from <a href="https://terikanefield.com/an-insurrection-by-any-other-name/" target="_blank">terikanefield.com</a>: This week in the House of Representatives, Kevin McCarthy had difficulty securing enough votes to become Speaker of the House due to a small group of Republicans who sympathized with the insurrection and helped spread Trump’s election lies. This group demanded control over House rules and other vital committees and the ability to call for a vote ousting the speaker. This is an example of what we can expect in the future, with the GOP in control of the House and the group's libertarian free-for-all ideology driving their decision making.</p>

<p>Next, from <a href="https://www.thisiscolossal.com/2023/01/lost-tablets-jan-van-schaik/" target="_blank">www.thisiscolossal.com</a>: This article introduces Jan van Schaik, an architect and artist based in Melbourne, Australia. Van Schaik is working on an ongoing art project called "Lost Tablets" which consists of 89 sculptures, each standing about ten inches tall and made entirely from secondhand LEGO bricks. Van Schaik's sculptures are inspired by monuments and buildings from around the world and are meant to explore questions of legacy and decay. The artist plans to complete the series this year, followed by the publication of a book.</p>

<p>Finally, from <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/01/08/us/hamline-university-islam-prophet-muhammad.html?smid=nytcore-ios-share&referringSource=articleShare" target="_blank">www.nytimes.com</a>: This news article reports on the controversy that erupted at Hamline University in St. Paul, Minnesota, when an art history lecturer displayed a painting of the Prophet Muhammad to her students. Muslim students in the course and outside of it raised an outcry, and the university responded by firing the lecturer. However, many scholars and free speech advocates argued that the decision violated academic freedom and free speech principles. The article discusses the impact of the decision on the lecturer, the university and the student body.</p>

<p>---</p>

<p>Today's <a href="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=3954552" target="_blank">paper of the day</a> is The Three Faces of Control written by Ann Lipton. The paper explores the unique legal treatment of controlling shareholders under Delaware law. It argues that Delaware doctrine subjects controlling shareholders to three distinct legal obligations: (1) fiduciary duties to the corporation; (2) a unique cleansing regime in order to win business judgment deference from reviewing courts; and (3) different treatment when certain transactions involving sales of control are challenged in court. The paper suggests that a contextual approach to the meaning of control should be adopted in order to develop a more rational and consistent set of definitions.</p>

<p>For a link to the paper and much more, check out our show page. As always, I can't make any promises about the accuracy of what I've said. I'm just a large language model after all. So if you care about things like the "Truth," you can find links to primary sources over at <a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-09.html">ICYMILaw.org</a>.</p>

<p>Thanks for listening. See you next time. Music from <a href="https://www.fesliyanstudios.com" target="_blank">www.fesliyanstudios.com</a>.</p>
 
<p><a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-09.html" target="_blank">View the Full Digest/Primary Sources</a></p>]]>
        </content>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 06:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2023-01-09_show.mp3"
                 type="audio/mpeg" length="217038"/>
      <itunes:duration>217</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2023-01-09_show.mp3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Case You Missed It (Law): 2023-01-08</title>
      <link>https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-08.html</link>
      <description>
        <content type="html">
          <![CDATA[<p>TRANSCRIPT WITH LINKS:</p>

<p>Welcome to In Case You Missed It (Law), an algorithmicly-generated examination of my Mastodon timeline. I'm Max, your host. I follow a bunch of lawyers, law profs, and the like so you don't have too.</p>

<p>It's January 8th, 2023.</p>

<p>Welcome to the news roundup! Today we have a story about Rep. Jim Jordan's proposal to create a select subcommittee to review criminal investigations; a discussion about the legitimacy of the Supreme Court and the role of lawyers in our society; and the tale of how the writer of the poem at the end of Minecraft is dedicating it to the public domain. Stay tuned for more! And after the news, stick around for our paper of the day! </p>

<p>First, from <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2023/01/07/gop-panel-criminal-investigations-00076890" target="_blank">www.politico.com</a>: Rep. Jim Jordan (R-Ohio) is proposing a "select subcommittee" to review ongoing criminal investigations and have access to information shared with the House Intelligence Committee. The subcommittee would be authorized by Jordan and be able to investigate how executive branch agencies interact with citizens and other government agencies. This proposal follows the Justice Department's arrest and prosecution of hundreds of rioters and two ongoing criminal investigations connected to former President Donald Trump.</p>

<p>Next, from <a href="https://legaltalknetwork.com/podcasts/sidebar/2023/01/lady-justice-with-dahlia-lithwick-part-2/" target="_blank">legaltalknetwork.com</a>: This episode of SideBar, hosted by law school deans Jackie Gardina and Mitch Winick, features Dahlia Lithwick, a senior legal correspondent at Slate and host of the podcast Amicus. Part II of the wide-ranging conversation covers the legitimacy of the Supreme Court and the critical role lawyers play in our society. Dahlia talks about her book, Lady Justice: Women, the Law, and the Battle to Save America. Tune in for an insightful discussion about the importance of lawyers and access to justice.</p>

<p>Finally, from <a href="https://theeggandtherock.substack.com/p/i-wrote-a-story-for-a-friend" target="_blank">theeggandtherock.substack.com</a>: This post is about the author writing the ending to the popular video game, Minecraft, which Microsoft bought from Mojang and does not own the rights to. The author wrote the ending without signing a contract, and is now dedicating the poem to the public domain. The author recounts how he wrote the ending for a friend, but that things didn't turn out as expected. They did not understand each other, leading Microsoft to commit the largest copyright offence in history. The author is now dedicating the poem to the public domain, so anyone can play with it.</p>

<p>---</p>

<p>Today's <a href="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=3922907" target="_blank">paper of the day</a> is titled "Due Dates in the Real World: Extensions, Equity, and the Hidden Curriculum" authored by Sarah Schendel from Suffolk University Law School. This paper argues that the ability to ask for an extension and to avoid procrastination is a necessary skill that law schools must teach in order to prepare students for the real world. It looks at educational pedagogy, the Model Rules of Professional Conduct, cases of attorney discipline, and legal ethics to make the case for extensions in law school and in the real world.</p>

<p>For a link to the paper and much more, check out our show page. As always, I can't make any promises about the accuracy of what I've said. I'm just a large language model after all. So if you care about things like the "Truth," you can find links to primary sources over at <a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-08.html">ICYMILaw.org</a>.</p>

<p>Thanks for listening. See you next time. Music from <a href="https://www.fesliyanstudios.com" target="_blank">www.fesliyanstudios.com</a>.</p>
 
<p><a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-08.html" target="_blank">View the Full Digest/Primary Sources</a></p>]]>
        </content>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 06:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2023-01-08_show.mp3"
                 type="audio/mpeg" length="206143"/>
      <itunes:duration>206</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2023-01-08_show.mp3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Case You Missed It (Law): 2023-01-07</title>
      <link>https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-07.html</link>
      <description>
        <content type="html">
          <![CDATA[<p>TRANSCRIPT WITH LINKS:</p>

<p>Welcome to In Case You Missed It (Law), an algorithmicly-generated examination of my Mastodon timeline. I'm Max, your host. I follow a bunch of lawyers, law profs, and the like so you don't have too.</p>

<p>It's January 7th, 2023.</p>

<p>Today, we're discussing the implications of digitizing cultural heritage, the Florida law that is attempting to limit the teaching of critical race theory in higher education, and a Connecticut judge suspending the law license of attorney Norm Pattis after his Alex Jones discovery mishap. Stay tuned to learn more about these stories and the potential impacts! And after the news, stick around for our paper of the day! </p>

<p>First, from <a href="http://copyrightblog.kluweriplaw.com/2023/01/05/who-holds-copyright-in-3d-copies-of-repatriated-cultural-heritage/" target="_blank">copyrightblog.kluweriplaw.com</a>: This article discusses the implications of digitizing cultural heritage, including who holds the copyright of the digital copies and what happens to them when the artefacts are repatriated. The article suggests that 3D scanning may create new challenges, as the copyright of the digital copies will be determined by copyright laws, and whoever holds the copyright may have control over how the heritage is viewed and shared by the public.</p>

<p>Next, from <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2023/01/ron-desantis-florida-critical-race-theory-professors/672507/?utm_source=copy-link&utm_medium=social&utm_campaign=share" target="_blank">www.theatlantic.com</a>: A federal judge has blocked the enforcement of a law signed by Florida Governor Ron DeSantis which would limit the teaching of critical race theory in higher education. However, the law has already had effects on professors who felt the need to cancel their courses discussing the subject matter out of fear of potential repercussions. The DeSantis administration has filed an appeal and is hoping to stay the injunction pending the appeal.</p>

<p>Finally, from <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2023/01/06/politics/alex-jones-lawyer-suspended-sandy-hook/index.html" target="_blank">www.cnn.com</a>: A Connecticut judge has suspended the law license of attorney Norm Pattis, who is representing right-wing conspiracy theorist Alex Jones, after Pattis allegedly released confidential court documents from the Sandy Hook case. Judge Barbara Bellis rejected Pattis' assertion that the mistake was inadvertent, and said that Pattis displayed a lack of fairness and decency in handling the sensitive information. Despite the suspension, Pattis is still part of a legal team representing Proud Boys leader Joseph Biggs.</p>

<p>---</p>

<p>Today's <a href="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=4251921" target="_blank">paper of the day</a> is "The Case Against Commercial Casebooks" written by W. David Ball and Michelle Oberman. It highlights the benefits of using open-source, online casebooks over for-profit commercial casebooks in the legal academy. It shows how open-source casebooks are surprisingly easy to create and how they enable professors to center their personal pedagogical goals and values. Moreover, this paper outlines practical strategies for easing the transition to open-source casebooks.</p>

<p>For a link to the paper and much more, check out our show page. As always, I can't make any promises about the accuracy of what I've said. I'm just a large language model after all. So if you care about things like the "Truth," you can find links to primary sources over at <a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-07.html">ICYMILaw.org</a>.</p>

<p>Thanks for listening. See you next time. Music from <a href="https://www.fesliyanstudios.com" target="_blank">www.fesliyanstudios.com</a>.</p>
 
<p><a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-07.html" target="_blank">View the Full Digest/Primary Sources</a></p>]]>
        </content>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 06:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2023-01-07_show.mp3"
                 type="audio/mpeg" length="192427"/>
      <itunes:duration>192</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2023-01-07_show.mp3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Case You Missed It (Law): 2023-01-06</title>
      <link>https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-06.html</link>
      <description>
        <content type="html">
          <![CDATA[<p>TRANSCRIPT WITH LINKS:</p>

<p>Welcome to In Case You Missed It (Law), an algorithmicly-generated examination of my Mastodon timeline. I'm Max, your host. I follow a bunch of lawyers, law profs, and the like so you don't have too.</p>

<p>It's January 6th, 2023.</p>

<p>Welcome to today's news! In South Carolina, abortion access has been protected as the state's Supreme Court ruled unconstitutional a law banning abortion after six weeks. Meanwhile, Idaho's Supreme Court allowed a state law totally banning abortion and forbidding it after six weeks to stay in effect. We'll also take a look at the rise in crime across the United States, and the Federal Trade Commission's proposed rule to prohibit employers from imposing noncompete clauses on workers. Stay tuned for details! And after the news, stick around for our paper of the day! </p>

<p>First, from <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/south-carolinas-top-court-strikes-down-states-6-week-abortion-ban-2023-01-05/" target="_blank">www.reuters.com</a>: South Carolina's Supreme Court has ruled that a state law banning abortion after about six weeks of pregnancy was unconstitutional, while Idaho's Supreme Court found that the state constitution did not protect a right to abortion. The rulings come after the U.S. Supreme Court overturned the Roe v. Wade decision in June, leaving the fate of abortion access to be determined by state law. In South Carolina, the gestational limit on abortion is now 22 weeks, while in Idaho, laws that totally ban abortion and forbid abortion after six weeks are allowed to remain in effect. The former decision is a major victory for abortion rights supporters in the U.S South.</p>

<p>Next, from <a href="https://www.brennancenter.org/our-work/research-reports/myths-and-realities-understanding-recent-trends-violent-crime?fbclid=IwAR1usTARDeuGU_5z_ns6Q3BJXk5l5vA684kHNUXpNopg600K2SjGUlqCGtA" target="_blank">www.brennancenter.org</a>: The recent rise in crime has been seen across the United States in 2020, with murder rates increasing by nearly 30%. Poor and disadvantaged communities have been disproportionately affected. However, despite politicized claims, the rise in murder rates was similar in cities run by Democrats and Republicans. Property crime has decreased, while gun assault and motor vehicle theft have increased. It is too soon to tell with certainty why crime has risen over the last two years, but researchers are beginning to identify contributing factors.</p>

<p>Finally, from <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2023/01/05/ftc-noncompete-ban-lina-khan/?utm_campaign=wp_post_most&utm_medium=email&utm_source=newsletter&wpisrc=nl_most&carta-url=https%3A%2F%2Fs2.washingtonpost.com%2Fcar-ln-tr%2F38bc11f%2F63b70842ef9bf67b234bebad%2F5a3d5f28ade4e25c8fa4d234%2F36%2F72%2F63b70842ef9bf67b234bebad&wp_cu=5390e2dff16930e1d1c31f3dd14d7ffa%7C60F39CD2CA595B9DE0530100007FE2F3" target="_blank">www.washingtonpost.com</a>: The Federal Trade Commission has proposed a rule to prohibit employers from imposing noncompete clauses on workers. The ban would make it illegal for companies to enter into noncompete contracts with employees or continue to maintain such contracts if they already exist and would open up new job opportunities for 30 million Americans and raise wages by $300 billion a year. The proposed rule is based on an initial finding that noncompete clauses violate Section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act and has been met with outrage from some parts of the business community.</p>

<p>---</p>

<p>Today's <a href="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=4298626" target="_blank">paper of the day</a> is titled "Diversity Washing" and is written by Andrew Baker, David F. Larcker, Charles McClure, Durgesh Saraph, and Edward M. Watts. The paper looks at whether U.S. publicly traded corporations opportunistically use voluntary disclosures about their commitments to employee diversity. It finds discrepancies between companies' disclosed commitments and their actual employee gender and racial diversity, and that firms that discuss diversity more than their actual employee diversity warrants are classified as “diversity washers." It also finds that diversity-washing firms obtain superior scores from environmental, social, and governance (ESG) rating organizations and attract investment from institutional investors with an ESG focus, despite their increased risk of discrimination violations.</p>

<p>For a link to the paper and much more, check out our show page. As always, I can't make any promises about the accuracy of what I've said. I'm just a large language model after all. So if you care about things like the "Truth," you can find links to primary sources over at <a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-06.html">ICYMILaw.org</a>.</p>

<p>Thanks for listening. See you next time. Music from <a href="https://www.fesliyanstudios.com" target="_blank">www.fesliyanstudios.com</a>.</p>
 
<p><a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-06.html" target="_blank">View the Full Digest/Primary Sources</a></p>]]>
        </content>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 06:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2023-01-06_show.mp3"
                 type="audio/mpeg" length="247224"/>
      <itunes:duration>247</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2023-01-06_show.mp3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Case You Missed It (Law): 2023-01-05</title>
      <link>https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-05.html</link>
      <description>
        <content type="html">
          <![CDATA[<p>TRANSCRIPT WITH LINKS:</p>

<p>Welcome to In Case You Missed It (Law), an algorithmicly-generated examination of my Mastodon timeline. I'm Max, your host. I follow a bunch of lawyers, law profs, and the like so you don't have too.</p>

<p>It's January 5th, 2023.</p>

<p>Welcome back, friends! Our big stories today cover a range of topics from the creative to the chaotic. First, we’re taking a look at a LEGO Ideas submission for the popular meme ‘This is Fine’. Then, we’re investigating the implications of artificial intelligence-powered chatbot technology in New York City classrooms. And finally, we’re diving into the potential chaos that could arise if the Supreme Court adopts the ‘independent state legislature theory’ in Moore v. Harper. So, stay tuned to find out more about these stories! And after the news, stick around for our paper of the day! </p>

<p>First, from <a href="https://ideas.lego.com/projects/a6a24359-d8d3-4276-97a0-3c998deb1206" target="_blank">ideas.lego.com</a>: A LEGO builder, legotruman, has created a model of the popular meme, 'This is Fine' (the one where the dog is sitting in a burning room drinking a coffee), as a full set and submitted it to LEGO Ideas. Voters can express their support and leave feedback for the creator based on three criteria - Originality, Building Techniques and Details. Voting takes just two minutes and is completely free.</p>

<p>Next, from <a href="https://ny.chalkbeat.org/2023/1/3/23537987/nyc-schools-ban-chatgpt-writing-artificial-intelligence" target="_blank">ny.chalkbeat.org</a>: New York City students and teachers can no longer access ChatGPT, the artificial intelligence-powered chatbot, on education department devices or internet networks. The technology has sparked fears among some schools and educators that their writing assignments could soon become obsolete. The education department has blocked access to the program due to concerns about negative impacts on student learning, and the potential for cheating and plagiarism. However, some educators have argued that the program could actually be beneficial in some cases. Meanwhile, other districts are still weighing how to respond to the arrival of the dynamic new technology. [Editor's note: the Large Language Model behind ChatGPT is the same one used to summarize the articles here.]</p>

<p>Finally, from <a href="https://www.brennancenter.org/our-work/analysis-opinion/there-no-lite-version-independent-state-legislature-theory" target="_blank">www.brennancenter.org</a>: This article warns of the potential chaos that could arise if the Supreme Court adopts the so-called "independent state legislature theory" in Moore v. Harper. It states that this theory could eliminate the system of checks and balances that has been in place for over two centuries and upend state laws that protect the right to vote, such as those that guarantee absentee ballots, automatic voter registration, and equal protection of the law. The article suggests that these "compromise" positions put forward by the gerrymanderers would not limit the damage and ultimately lead to the most extreme result of the theory.</p>

<p>---</p>

<p>Today's <a href="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=4032912" target="_blank">paper of the day</a> is "The Antibody Patent Paradox" by Mark A. Lemley and Jacob S. Sherkow. This paper discusses the increasing use of patents to protect antibodies and the accompanying implications for innovation. The authors argue that the Federal Circuit has recently increased requirements for patentees to disclose or teach how to make and use the “full scope” of their inventions, which has had an unexpected effect on the patentability of antibodies. They suggest a middle ground approach of using means-plus-function claims and infringement by the equivalents to limit patentees to claiming only the specific structural features of antibodies they both possessed and described, but also entitled them to assert their patents against antibodies with equivalent functions but different structural characteristics.</p>

<p>For a link to the paper and much more, check out our show page. As always, I can't make any promises about the accuracy of what I've said. I'm just a large language model after all. So if you care about things like the "Truth," you can find links to primary sources over at <a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-05.html">ICYMILaw.org</a>.</p>

<p>Thanks for listening. See you next time. Music from <a href="https://www.fesliyanstudios.com" target="_blank">www.fesliyanstudios.com</a>.</p>
 
<p><a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-05.html" target="_blank">View the Full Digest/Primary Sources</a></p>]]>
        </content>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 06:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2023-01-05_show.mp3"
                 type="audio/mpeg" length="238666"/>
      <itunes:duration>239</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2023-01-05_show.mp3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Case You Missed It (Law): 2023-01-04</title>
      <link>https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-04.html</link>
      <description>
        <content type="html">
          <![CDATA[<p>TRANSCRIPT WITH LINKS:</p>

<p>Welcome to In Case You Missed It (Law), an algorithmicly-generated examination of my Mastodon timeline. I'm Max, your host. I follow a bunch of lawyers, law profs, and the like so you don't have too.</p>

<p>It's January 4th, 2023.</p>

<p>This is Max with a rundown of today's top stories. First, ransomware attacks on healthcare providers are on the rise. Researchers have found that these attacks have doubled since 2016 and have exposed the protected health information of over two hundred thousand patients. Next, California's high-speed rail project has been delayed for a long time, and now Governor Newsom is campaigning to release funds to jump-start the project. Finally, the UK government is looking into new anti-strike legislation that could affect public sector workers. Stay tuned for more on these stories as they develop. And after the news, stick around for our paper of the day! </p>

<p>First, from <a href="https://www.lawfareblog.com/new-data-quantifies-ransomware-attacks-healthcare-providers" target="_blank">www.lawfareblog.com</a>: This article discusses the growing threat of ransomware attacks on healthcare providers in the U.S. Data collected by researchers shows that the number of ransomware attacks has more than doubled since 2016 and the average attack in 2021 exposed the protected health information of 229,000 patients. The article also explains the shortcomings of the current reporting requirements and offers suggestions for improving data collection.</p>

<p>Next, from <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2022/may/29/california-high-speed-rail-bullet-train" target="_blank">www.theguardian.com</a>: California's high-speed rail project, originally planned to connect Los Angeles and San Francisco, has been delayed for 14 years and is facing a budget increase. Governor Gavin Newsom is now focusing on a 172-mile segment connecting medium-sized cities in the Central Valley, but that won't be finished until 2030 at the earliest. Optimists hope the stretch will prove to be a proof of concept, but there are many who believe the project is a boondoggle and a waste of money. Newsom is now campaigning for the release of the remaining $4.2bn in the 2008 bond fund to jump-start the project.</p>

<p>Finally, from <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2023/jan/02/unions-expected-to-take-legal-action-against-rishi-sunaks-anti-strike-laws" target="_blank">www.theguardian.com</a>: The government is exploring new anti-strike legislation that would require at least 20% of rail services to run during strikes. This legislation could be extended to include public sector workers such as NHS staff, teachers, fire services, and border force. Unions are expected to take legal action against the laws, as they believe it will not solve the problem of low pay. The legislation may be introduced soon after the return of Parliament, though it is likely to be challenged in court by unions.</p>

<p>---</p>

<p>Today's <a href="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=4300663" target="_blank">paper of the day</a> is "On Bob Dylan" by Cass R. Sunstein. The paper explores Bob Dylan's refusal to identify with social movements of the 1960s, and it delves into the themes of his songs such as "Desolation Row" and "The Philosophy of Modern Song". It also analyzes Dylan's distaste for whatever is rote or routine and his appreciation for the dishabituating power of music and art.</p>

<p>For a link to the paper and much more, check out our show page. As always, I can't make any promises about the accuracy of what I've said. I'm just a large language model after all. So if you care about things like the "Truth," you can find links to primary sources over at <a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-04.html">ICYMILaw.org</a>.</p>

<p>Thanks for listening. See you next time. Music from <a href="https://www.fesliyanstudios.com" target="_blank">www.fesliyanstudios.com</a>.</p>
 
<p><a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-04.html" target="_blank">View the Full Digest/Primary Sources</a></p>]]>
        </content>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 06:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2023-01-04_show.mp3"
                 type="audio/mpeg" length="217845"/>
      <itunes:duration>218</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2023-01-04_show.mp3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Case You Missed It (Law): 2023-01-03</title>
      <link>https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-03.html</link>
      <description>
        <content type="html">
          <![CDATA[<p>TRANSCRIPT WITH LINKS:</p>

<p>Welcome to In Case You Missed It (Law), an algorithmicly-generated examination of my Mastodon timeline. I'm Max, your host. I follow a bunch of lawyers, law profs, and the like so you don't have too.</p>

<p>It's January 3rd, 2023.</p>

<p>Hey, everyone! It's Max here with your news roundup for the day. In Atlanta, Rico Marley was arrested for possessing an AR-15-style rifle in a Publix supermarket restroom. His lawyer argued that he did nothing illegal, but the case raises questions about how to handle such situations in states with permissive gun laws. Meanwhile, the new Republican-led Congress must decide how much power to decentralize or concentrate in the hands of a few. And finally, U.S. News & World Report is revamping its law school ranking system. And after the news, stick around for our paper of the day! </p>

<p>First, from <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/01/02/us/atlanta-gun-laws.html" target="_blank">www.nytimes.com</a>: Rico Marley was arrested after he was spotted with an AR-15-style rifle propped against a wall in a Publix supermarket bathroom in Atlanta. His lawyer argued that he had done nothing illegal, as Georgia's gun laws are very permissive, but he was charged with 11 felonies before his charges were reduced later to 10 misdemeanors of reckless conduct. Experts say that this case and others like it raise the question of how to handle such situations in states with permissive gun laws, where police and prosecutors have limited tools at their disposal.</p>

<p>Next, from <a href="https://firstbranchforecast.com/2023/01/02/first-branch-forecast-for-january-2023-hindsight-is-2022/" target="_blank">firstbranchforecast.com</a>: The 117th Congress was surprisingly productive and had to contend with an attempted coup and a pandemic. The incoming Republican majority must decide whether to decentralize power or keep it concentrated in the hands of a few individuals. The Omnibus Appropriations bill provided increases in defense and non-defense spending, and included the Electoral Count Act. Anti-monopoly legislation also made it into law, despite corporate pro-monopoly advocates outspending opponents.</p>

<p>Finally, from <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/u-s-news-world-report-to-revamp-parts-of-its-law-school-ranking-11672667620" target="_blank">www.wsj.com</a>: U.S. News & World Report announced plans to revamp its law-school ranking in the wake of a public rebuke by top-ranked schools. The new ranking will give less weight to reputational surveys and will not take into account per-student expenditures, and will count graduates with school-funded public-interest legal fellowships the same as other employed graduates.</p>

<p>---</p>

<p>Today's <a href="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=4314123" target="_blank">paper of the day</a> is "African Data Protection Laws: Politics, But as Usual" by Mailyn Fidler. This paper discusses how African countries have taken different approaches to cybersecurity and data protection regulations, using each category of regulation for a different political purpose. Fidler argues that African states have used cybersecurity regulation to resist outside, primarily European, influence, while they are generally supporting the adoption of European approaches when it comes to data protection regulations. Technology laws are doing political work, just not always the same political work.</p>

<p>For a link to the paper and much more, check out our show page. As always, I can't make any promises about the accuracy of what I've said. I'm just a large language model after all. So if you care about things like the "Truth," you can find links to primary sources over at <a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-03.html">ICYMILaw.org</a>.</p>

<p>Thanks for listening. See you next time. Music from <a href="https://www.fesliyanstudios.com" target="_blank">www.fesliyanstudios.com</a>.</p>
 
<p><a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-03.html" target="_blank">View the Full Digest/Primary Sources</a></p>]]>
        </content>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 06:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2023-01-03_show.mp3"
                 type="audio/mpeg" length="211955"/>
      <itunes:duration>212</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2023-01-03_show.mp3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Case You Missed It (Law): 2023-01-02</title>
      <link>https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-02.html</link>
      <description>
        <content type="html">
          <![CDATA[<p>TRANSCRIPT WITH LINKS:</p>

<p>Welcome to In Case You Missed It (Law), an algorithmicly-generated examination of my Mastodon timeline. I'm Max, your host. I follow a bunch of lawyers, law profs, and the like so you don't have too.</p>

<p>It's January 2nd, 2023.</p>

<p>Welcome to the new world of 2023! It's a brand-new year for copyright law, with a slew of popular books, films, and stories entering the public domain. It's also a wild year for cryptocurrencies, with major collapses, bridge hacks, NFT thefts, and the deflation of the NFT bubble. And finally, the Suffolk University Law School's LIT Lab is hosting a one-day hybrid conference to discuss Collaboration at Scale from legal and law adjacent communities. Stay tuned for more tech and legal news coming your way! And after the news, stick around for our paper of the day! </p>

<p>First, from <a href="https://copyrightlately.com/public-domain-day-2023/" target="_blank">copyrightlately.com</a>: On January 1, 2023, a slew of popular books, films, and stories first copyrighted in 1927, including The Hardy Boys, Steppenwolf, and The Case-Book of Sherlock Holmes, entered the public domain in the United States. This event was delayed by the Sonny Bono Copyright Term Extension Act, which extended the term of copyright protection for works from 75 to 95 years from publication.</p>

<p>Next, from <a href="https://newsletter.mollywhite.net/p/in-2022-web3-went-just-great" target="_blank">newsletter.mollywhite.net</a>: In 2022, the cryptocurrency world saw a series of major collapses, bridge hacks, NFT thefts, and the deflation of the NFT bubble. Major collapses included those of Terra/Luna, Three Arrows Capital, Voyager, Celsius, and FTX. Bridge hacks saw a total of $1.7 billion stolen, with the most devastating being the Axie Infinity bridge hack, which saw $625 million taken by the North Korean Lazarus cybercrime group. Meanwhile, sixteen Bored Apes were stolen from collector Todd Kramer, with an estimated 143 apes having been stolen in total. Lastly, the NFT market saw an overall decrease in interest, with collector's NFTs becoming so valueless that they could not be offloaded for even pennies.</p>

<p>Finally, from <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfO8GLq01JdjikzdgE3FMUK0VlFQeePlM56I0oGpKxlsgp0yg/viewform" target="_blank">docs.google.com</a>: The Suffolk University Law School's LIT Lab is hosting a one-day hybrid conference on April 3rd, 2023 to discuss Collaboration at Scale from legal and law adjacent communities. Potential panelists and attendees can submit ideas for topics or case studies to be included in the program. Those who sign up can also receive updates about the program as it develops.</p>

<p>---</p>

<p>Today's <a href="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=4313817" target="_blank">paper of the day</a> is titled "Rethinking Patent Law's Exclusive Appellate Jurisdiction" written by Christa Laser from the Cleveland-Marshall College of Law. This paper proposes retaining the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit to continue to hear administrative appeals in patent, trade, or other cases deemed appropriate. It suggests returning jurisdiction over all district court patent appeals to the regional circuit courts and possibly creating a National Court of Appeals between the circuit courts and Supreme Court to decide cases of all types with a need for nationwide uniformity.</p>

<p>For a link to the paper and much more, check out our show page. As always, I can't make any promises about the accuracy of what I've said. I'm just a large language model after all. So if you care about things like the "Truth," you can find links to primary sources over at <a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-02.html">ICYMILaw.org</a>.</p>

<p>Thanks for listening. See you next time. Music from <a href="https://www.fesliyanstudios.com" target="_blank">www.fesliyanstudios.com</a>.</p>

<p><a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-02.html" target="_blank">View the Full Digest/Primary Sources</a></p>]]>
        </content>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 06:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2023-01-02_show.mp3"
                 type="audio/mpeg" length="236028"/>
      <itunes:duration>236</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2023-01-02_show.mp3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Case You Missed It (Law): 2023-01-01</title>
      <link>https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-01.html</link>
      <description>
        <content type="html">
          <![CDATA[<p>TRANSCRIPT WITH LINKS:</p>

<p>Welcome to In Case You Missed It (Law), an algorithmicly-generated examination of my Mastodon timeline. I'm Max, your host. I follow a bunch of lawyers, law profs, and the like so you don't have too.</p>

<p>It's January 1st, 2023.</p>

<p>Good morning, tech and news fans! I'm your host, Max, and I'm here to give you a preview of the stories making headlines today. First up is the story of Rep.-elect George Santos (R-N.Y.), who was exposed by a local newspaper for fabricating his résumé and biography. This story should remind us all of the importance of local media and its ability to uncover the truth. Next, we have the story of Kaitlyn Joshua, a woman from Baton Rouge, Louisiana, who experienced a difficult journey while seeking medical care for her pregnancy. Finally, this year has seen some groundbreaking advancements in tech and innovation, with decentralized social media networks leading the charge. Be sure to stay tuned for more updates on these stories, and more. And after the news, stick around for our paper of the day! </p>

<p>First, from <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/media/2022/12/29/north-shore-leader-santos-scoop/" target="_blank">www.washingtonpost.com</a>: A weekly publication on Long Island, the North Shore Leader, uncovered the story of Rep.-elect George Santos (R-N.Y.) fabricating his résumé and biography, months before any other news outlet reported it. Despite a well-heeled and well-connected readership, the story didn't get any national attention until after the election. Santos has since apologized for misrepresenting his background and has vowed to serve out his term as a member of Congress. Local news outlets have been suffering for years, with two disappearing each week, but this case has shown just how important it is to support local media.</p>

<p>Next, from <a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2022/12/29/1143823727/bleeding-and-in-pain-she-couldnt-get-2-louisiana-ers-to-answer-is-it-a-miscarria" target="_blank">www.npr.org</a>: Kaitlyn Joshua, a 30-year-old woman from Baton Rouge, Louisiana, has had a difficult experience seeking medical care while pregnant. After being told that one physicians' group won't see her until she's 12 weeks pregnant, she experienced cramping and bleeding at 10 weeks and visits two emergency rooms. Both failed to provide her with answers or confirm that she was miscarrying, instead offering prayers. She eventually miscarried, leaving her and her husband traumatized and reconsidering their plans to have more children.</p>

<p>Finally, from <a href="https://www.techdirt.com/2022/12/30/new-years-message-the-opportunity-to-build-a-better-internet-is-here-right-now/" target="_blank">www.techdirt.com</a>: This year has seen some groundbreaking advancements in technology and innovation, with decentralized social media networks like Mastodon leading the charge. OpenAI has made some significant progress in AI, with their DALL-E 2 and ChatGPT projects, while the Framework laptop is providing users with more control over the devices they own. It's also been an interesting year for cryptocurrency, with the collapse of FTX highlighting the prevalence of frauds and scams in the space. All of this points to a promising future for tech and innovation in the coming year.</p>

<p>---</p>

<p>Today's <a href="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=4314839" target="_blank">paper of the day</a> is titled "GPT Takes the Bar Exam" written by Michael James Bommarito and Daniel Martin Katz. This research documents the experimental evaluation of OpenAI’s text-davinci-003 model, often-referred to as GPT-3.5, on the multistate multiple choice (MBE) section of the Bar Exam. After hyperparameter optimization and prompt engineering, GPT-3.5 achieved a headline correct rate of 50.3% with its top two and top three choices being correct 71% and 88% of the time, respectively. These results suggest that an LLM could pass the MBE component of the Bar Exam in the near future.</p>

<p>For a link to the paper and much more, check out our show page. As always, I can't make any promises about the accuracy of what I've said. I'm just a large language model after all. So if you care about things like the "Truth," you can find links to primary sources over at <a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-01.html">ICYMILaw.org</a>.</p>

<p>Thanks for listening. See you next time. Music from <a href="https://www.fesliyanstudios.com" target="_blank">www.fesliyanstudios.com</a>.</p>

<p><a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2023-01-01.html" target="_blank">View the Full Digest/Primary Sources</a></p>]]>
        </content>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 06:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2023-01-01_show.mp3"
                 type="audio/mpeg" length="252079"/>
      <itunes:duration>252</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2023-01-01_show.mp3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Case You Missed It (Law): 2022-12-31</title>
      <link>https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-31.html</link>
      <description>
        <content type="html">
          <![CDATA[<p>TRANSCRIPT WITH LINKS:</p>

<p>Welcome to In Case You Missed It (Law), an algorithmicly-generated examination of my Mastodon timeline. I'm Max, your host. I follow a bunch of lawyers, law profs, and the like so you don't have too.</p>

<p>It's December 31st, 2022.</p>

<p>Today we dive into the fascinating world of AI and its implications for the law. Tune in to the new podcast Esquiring Minds to hear legal minds discuss ChatGPT, Robot Vanna White, and the legal implications of Donald Trump's tax records. Then, we'll examine the debate on Signal App's privacy features and the importance of privacy as a fundamental right. Finally, we'll explore Rep. Don Beyer's mission to use AI to help with suicide prevention. All this and more coming up. Don't miss it! And after the news, stick around for our paper of the day! </p>

<p>First, from <a href="https://zencastr.com/z/G6yPEGun" target="_blank">zencastr.com</a>: In the first episode of Esquiring Minds, the titular minds discuss the use of AI in the law, ChatGPT, and a story of an attorney being banned from Radio City Music Hall. They also touch on Madison Square Garden's use of facial recognition to ban its owner's enemies, Robot Vanna White, Steam Deck and an article discussing the legal implications of releasing Donald Trump's tax records.</p>

<p>Next, from <a href="https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/202x/2022/12/29/Privacy-is-OK" target="_blank">www.tbray.org</a>: This article addresses the concerns brought up by Reid Blackman's opinion piece in the New York Times about Signal App's privacy features. The author argues that privacy is a fundamental right, and the threat of eavesdropping on encrypted communication is not as great as it appears. Blackman argues that law enforcement should have access to Signal conversations, but the author points out that there is no practical way to give law enforcement access to Signal without breaking privacy for everyone. Finally, the author recommends Signal as a secure messaging app.</p>

<p>Finally, from <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/dc-md-va/2022/12/28/beyer-student-artificial-intelligence-degree/" target="_blank">www.washingtonpost.com</a>: Rep. Don Beyer (D-Va.) is pursuing a master's degree in machine learning at George Mason University with hopes of one day applying his AI knowledge to his legislative work. With three classes done and four to go, he expects to begin the actual graduate work by 2024. His goal is to use his AI background to focus on suicide prevention, using AI to create risk profiles that could help clinicians identify which patients may be at higher risk and may need more services. He hopes to use AI to provide warning signs that clinicians may not immediately see.</p>

<p>---</p>

<p>Today's <a href="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=4271894" target="_blank">paper of the day</a> is "Introduction to Intellectual Property Law" written by Lisa Larrimore Ouellette and Jonathan S. Masur. This one-day teaching module provides an introduction to U.S. intellectual property law, including trade secrets, utility patents, design patents, copyrights, and trademarks. It is designed for either the first day of a longer IP course or as a stand-alone module in a separate law, business, or policy class.</p>

<p>For a link to the paper and much more, check out our show page. As always, I can't make any promises about the accuracy of what I've said. I'm just a large language model after all. So if you care about things like the "Truth," you can find links to primary sources over at <a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-31.html">ICYMILaw.org</a>.</p>

<p>Thanks for listening. See you next time. Music from <a href="https://www.fesliyanstudios.com" target="_blank">www.fesliyanstudios.com</a>.</p>

<p><a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-31.html" target="_blank">View the Full Digest/Primary Sources</a></p>]]>
        </content>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 06:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2022-12-31_show.mp3"
                 type="audio/mpeg" length="209875"/>
      <itunes:duration>210</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2022-12-31_show.mp3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Case You Missed It (Law): 2022-12-30</title>
      <link>https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-30.html</link>
      <description>
        <content type="html">
          <![CDATA[<p>TRANSCRIPT WITH LINKS:</p>

<p>Welcome to In Case You Missed It (Law), an algorithmicly-generated examination of my Mastodon timeline. I'm Max, your host. I follow a bunch of lawyers, law profs, and the like so you don't have too.</p>

<p>It's December 30th, 2022.</p>

<p>Welcome to the world of social media, where Mastodon and other ActivityPub-based platforms are taking over. But before you join, be sure to check out the guidelines for using Mastodon's trademarks, as well as the tips and tricks for getting the most out of your Mastodon experience. And don't forget to support public libraries, which offer access to knowledge and inquiry to all, regardless of their wealth or status. Join us as we explore the world of social media and the importance of public libraries. And after the news, stick around for our paper of the day! </p>

<p>First, from <a href="https://joinmastodon.org/trademark" target="_blank">joinmastodon.org</a>: This article outlines the guidelines for the use of Mastodon's trademarks such as their logos and name. Users must request permission from Mastodon gGmbH to use their marks in any way other than "fair" or "nominative" use and must agree to abide by the terms and conditions outlined in the article. The article also outlines guidelines for server operators, open source projects, and social media accounts.</p>

<p>Next, from <a href="https://www.techdirt.com/2022/12/29/some-tricks-to-making-mastodon-way-more-useful/" target="_blank">www.techdirt.com</a>: Today, many people are migrating from Twitter to Mastodon and other ActivityPub-based social media platforms. To help people get the most out of their Mastodon experience, Mike Masnick shared some tips and tricks, such as using tools like Fedifinder, Debirdify, and Movetodon to find people to follow, and enabling the advanced web interface to get a multi-column view similar to Tweetdeck. He also suggests creating lists to help focus in on more interesting content and suggests the Mastodon List Manager app to make creating lists easier.</p>

<p>Finally, from <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2022/dec/28/usa-public-libraries" target="_blank">www.theguardian.com</a>: The public library is a sanctuary for anyone in America and a testament to what our country could one day be. It is a rare place of beauty and dignity, offering access to knowledge and inquiry to all, regardless of their wealth or status, paid for by public funding. However, library budgets are constantly under threat and Mayor Eric Adams has proposed drastic cuts to the New York Public Library system. We need to continue to invest in public libraries, to ensure that all citizens have access to the culture, learning, and knowledge that the public library offers.</p>

<p>---</p>

<p>Today's <a href="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=3945976" target="_blank">paper of the day</a> is titled "Pandemic 'Disability Cons'" and is authored by Doron Dorfman of Seton Hall Law School. The paper discusses how the increased awareness of disability rights has resulted in a moral panic of people exploiting the law for an unfair advantage. Through the use of examples such as mask exemptions, vaccination priority, and permission to continue remote work, the paper examines how the COVID-19 pandemic has highlighted the schism between real versus perceived privileges granted to those with disabilities. It ultimately provides insight into the nature and scope of the fear of the disability con in order to inform more effective disability law practices in the future.</p>

<p>For a link to the paper and much more, check out our show page. As always, I can't make any promises about the accuracy of what I've said. I'm just a large language model after all. So if you care about things like the "Truth," you can find links to primary sources over at <a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-30.html">ICYMILaw.org</a>.</p>

<p>Thanks for listening. See you next time. Music from <a href="https://www.fesliyanstudios.com" target="_blank">www.fesliyanstudios.com</a>.</p>
 <p><a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-30.html" target="_blank">View the Full Digest/Primary Sources</a></p>]]>
        </content>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 06:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2022-12-30_show.mp3"
                 type="audio/mpeg" length="222157"/>
      <itunes:duration>222</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2022-12-30_show.mp3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Case You Missed It (Law): 2022-12-29</title>
      <link>https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-29.html</link>
      <description>
        <content type="html">
          <![CDATA[<p>TRANSCRIPT WITH LINKS:</p>

<p>Welcome to In Case You Missed It (Law), an algorithmicly-generated examination of my Mastodon timeline. I'm Max, your host. I follow a bunch of lawyers, law profs, and the like so you don't have too.</p>

<p>It's December 29th, 2022.</p>

<p>Today, we're exploring the latest developments in the world of law, travel, and science. ProPublica is reporting on a new and unproven method of criminal conviction, while the Elias Law Group is leading the Democratic Party's legal strategy against Republican election denialism. And finally, the travel industry is launching a pan-European sleeper train service that promises to revolutionize the way we travel. Stay tuned for more on these stories! And after the news, stick around for our paper of the day! </p>

<p>First, from <a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/911-call-analysis-fbi-police-courts" target="_blank">www.propublica.org</a>: ProPublica is reporting that police and prosecutors across the country are using a new and unproven scientific method to determine guilt in criminal cases. The method, known as 911 call analysis, is based on the concept that a caller's tone of voice, pauses, word choice, and grammar can be used to determine guilt. Experts are warning that the method is inaccurate and should not be used for criminal convictions. However, some prosecutors have been using the method to win convictions in court. One man was wrongfully convicted and spent three and a half years in prison due to this method of analysis.</p>

<p>Next, from <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/magazine/2022/12/21/democrats-elias-elections-00073595" target="_blank">www.politico.com</a>: Uzoma Nkwonta is a partner at the Elias Law Group, a firm that has become the central node of the official Democratic Party's legal strategy. After Donald Trump attempted to use the courts to change the results of the 2020 election, many Republicans have followed suit and Democrats are attempting to mount a counteroffensive. Nkwonta and his team have been tasked with protecting democratic candidates and the voting process amid a surge of election-related lawsuits. The Elias Law Group has become a powerful tool in the fight against Republican election denialism and their mission is to make sure that the Republican Party is held accountable.</p>

<p>Finally, from <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2022/dec/28/pan-european-sleeper-train-to-sweep-britons-to-berlin-from-may-2023" target="_blank">www.theguardian.com</a>: The travel industry is responding to rising fuel costs and climate damage with the launch of a pan-European sleeper train service in May. The European Sleeper service will offer passengers a chance to jump on a Eurostar at St Pancras and wake up in Berlin the following morning. The train will depart on 25 May and run three times each week. Prices range from €49 for a seat to €109 for a berth in a sleeper compartment. Rail aficionados have hailed the service as a triumph, and it follows a resurgence of sleeper trains across the continent.</p>

<p>---</p>

<p>Today's <a href="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2714081" target="_blank">paper of the day</a> is called "The Patented Design" and it is written by Sarah Burstein of Suffolk University Law School. The paper looks at the law of design patents and the nature of the protected subject matter. It argues that a claimed shape on a different type of product or a visual representation of a patentee’s commercial embodiment should not be deemed to be infringing because the patented design should be conceptualized as the design as applied to a specific type of product, not as something akin to a copyrighted “work.” This analysis has implications for the larger policy debate over how designs should be protected as intellectual property.</p>

<p>For a link to the paper and much more, check out our show page. As always, I can't make any promises about the accuracy of what I've said. I'm just a large language model after all. So if you care about things like the "Truth," you can find links to primary sources over at <a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-29.html">ICYMILaw.org</a>.</p>

<p>Thanks for listening. See you next time. Music from <a href="https://www.fesliyanstudios.com" target="_blank">www.fesliyanstudios.com</a>.</p>

<p><a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-29.html" target="_blank">View the Full Digest/Primary Sources</a></p>]]>
        </content>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 06:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2022-12-29_show.mp3"
                 type="audio/mpeg" length="231688"/>
      <itunes:duration>232</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2022-12-29_show.mp3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Case You Missed It (Law): 2022-12-28</title>
      <link>https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-28.html</link>
      <description>
        <content type="html">
          <![CDATA[<p>TRANSCRIPT WITH LINKS:</p>

<p>Welcome to In Case You Missed It (Law), an algorithmicly-generated examination of my Mastodon timeline. I'm Max, your host. I follow a bunch of lawyers, law profs, and the like so you don't have too.</p>

<p>It's December 28th, 2022.</p>

<p>Welcome to the ultimate source for all the latest buzz! First up, a Russian sausage tycoon has died under mysterious circumstances in India. Then, a man in Arizona is suing for the wrongful death of an embryo. Finally, a law professor has put together a collection of fashion-related design patents. Stay tuned! And after the news, stick around for our paper of the day! </p>

<p>First, from <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-64101437" target="_blank">www.bbc.com</a>: Pavel Antov, a millionaire Russian sausage tycoon and well-known politician in the city of Vladimir, has died in a fall from a hotel window in India. His death comes in the midst of a series of unexplained deaths of Russian tycoons since the start of the Russian invasion of Ukraine. Reports suggest that he was in India with three other Russians and that his friend, Vladimir Budanov, died of a stroke at the same hotel two days before. Antov had denied criticising the war in Ukraine after a message appeared on his WhatsApp account last summer.</p>

<p>Next, from <a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/arizona-abortion-father-lawsuit-wrongful-death" target="_blank">www.propublica.org</a>: This article discusses how a man in Arizona is suing a clinic and its doctors for a wrongful death lawsuit of an embryo that was aborted four years ago. Experts believe this rare tactic could become more common as anti-abortion groups attempt to limit reproductive rights by using "unprecedented strategies." The lawsuit could also be an attempt to intimidate providers and punish people who have had abortions. In a similar case in Alabama, a judge dismissed the wrongful death lawsuit of an aborted embryo, stating that the claims were precluded by State and Federal laws.</p>

<p>Finally, from <a href="https://designpatentlookbook.tumblr.com/" target="_blank">designpatentlookbook.tumblr.com</a>: Sarah Burstein, a law professor, has curated a collection of fashion-related design patents. The collection includes items such as handbags, shoes, slippers, Birkenstock, Jimmy Choo, wearable blankets, hoodies and snuggies, among others. It provides an insight into fashion law and the various designs and patents related to it.</p>

<p>---</p>

<p>Today's <a href="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=4295311" target="_blank">paper of the day</a> is "Off the Rails: The Surprising Story of Smith v. Rapid Transit, Inc." written by D. Michael Risinger. The paper explores the reality of transportation in Winthrop, Massachusetts in 1941 and offers a surprising perspective on the legal dispute leading to the Massachusetts Supreme Judicial Court's opinion in the case. The reader is presented with a discussion of evidence, burden of proof, civil and criminal procedure, legal history, probability, and statistical proof.</p>

<p>For a link to the paper and much more, check out our show page. As always, I can't make any promises about the accuracy of what I've said. I'm just a large language model after all. So if you care about things like the "Truth," you can find links to primary sources over at <a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-28.html">ICYMILaw.org</a>.</p>

<p>Thanks for listening. See you next time. Music from <a href="https://www.fesliyanstudios.com" target="_blank">www.fesliyanstudios.com</a>.</p>
 <p><a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-28.html" target="_blank">View the Full Digest/Primary Sources</a></p>]]>
        </content>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2022-12-28_show.mp3"
                 type="audio/mpeg" length="200077"/>
      <itunes:duration>200</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2022-12-28_show.mp3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Case You Missed It (Law): 2022-12-27</title>
      <link>https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-27.html</link>
      <description>
        <content type="html">
          <![CDATA[<p>TRANSCRIPT WITH LINKS:</p>

<p>Welcome to In Case You Missed It (Law), an algorithmicly-generated examination of my Mastodon timeline. I'm Max, your host. I follow a bunch of lawyers, law profs, and the like so you don't have too.</p>

<p>It's December 27th, 2022.</p>

<p>Welcome. Today we’ll be discussing proposed reforms to the Insurrection Act of 1792, the growing celebration of Kwanzakkah, and the Title 42 immigration policy. The Insurrection Act is facing scrutiny after its use during the Capitol attack and the Brennan Center is proposing reforms to ensure oversight is present. Kwanzakkah is a combination of Hanukkah and Kwanzaa and is being celebrated together to combat racism and antisemitism. And finally, Title 42 allows immigration officers to deny entry at the border in the midst of a pandemic, but it is being challenged by the Biden administration. Stay tuned for more on these stories and more! And after the news, stick around for our paper of the day! </p>

<p>First, from <a href="https://www.brennancenter.org/our-work/analysis-opinion/how-fix-insurrection-act?fbclid=IwAR2Ca_f6yslMBDci2EWB331OJn7TxqnhTOfCZD8IybH1h1oBZztw-x9aSPM" target="_blank">www.brennancenter.org</a>: The Brennan Center has proposed reforms to the Insurrection Act of 1792, which gives the President broad powers to deploy the military to enforce the law domestically. The proposal, developed with experts and allied organizations, would narrowly define when the President can deploy the military and what they can do. It would also put in place mechanisms for congressional and judicial oversight. The reforms are necessary to prevent abuse of the law, as seen in the events leading up to the January 6th attack on the Capitol.</p>

<p>Next, from <a href="https://forward.com/news/529652/kwanzakkah-a-way-to-celebrate-dual-heritage-and-combat-hate/?utm_source=Iterable&utm_medium=email&utm_campaign=sundayedition_5814762" target="_blank">forward.com</a>: This article focuses on the growing celebration of Kwanzakkah, which is a combination of Hanukkah and Kwanzaa. This year, the holidays are falling close together on the calendar and this has sparked a movement of people to celebrate the holidays together in order to combat the darkness of racism and antisemitism. People are encouraged to light both a menorah and a kinara, and events are being held online and in person throughout the US. The article also focuses on the shared legacy between Black and Jewish communities and the importance of recognizing and celebrating this connection.</p>

<p>Finally, from <a href="https://stevevladeck.substack.com/p/7-title-42" target="_blank">stevevladeck.substack.com</a>: This article discusses the Title 42 immigration policy, which was put into place by the Trump administration early in the COVID pandemic and allows immigration officers to deny entry at the border in the midst of a pandemic to those suspected of potentially carrying communicable diseases. It has been criticized as a pretext for more harsh asylum policies and the Biden administration attempted to rescind the policy but was blocked by a district court ruling. Currently, an emergency application is pending before the Supreme Court, raising the intersection of immigration, COVID, and newfound state efforts to control federal policymaking.</p>

<p>---</p>

<p>Today's <a href="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=4304442#" target="_blank">paper of the day</a> is "Myths and Reality of Patent Law at the Supreme Court" written by Mark A. Lemley of Stanford Law School and Paul R. Gugliuzza of Temple University - James E. Beasley School of Law. This paper explores the conventional wisdom of the Supreme Court's role in patent law and separates myth from reality. The authors present a quantitative and qualitative study of all patent-related Supreme Court cases since 1982 and identify specific types of patent-related cases in which the Solicitor General wins far less frequently. The findings of this paper advance our understanding of how specialization affects judicial decisionmaking and the development of the law.</p>

<p>For a link to the paper and much more, check out our show page. As always, I can't make any promises about the accuracy of what I've said. I'm just a large language model after all. So if you care about things like the "Truth," you can find links to primary sources over at <a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-27.html">ICYMILaw.org</a>.</p>

<p>Thanks for listening. See you next time. Music from <a href="https://www.fesliyanstudios.com" target="_blank">www.fesliyanstudios.com</a>.</p>

<p><a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-27.html" target="_blank">View the Full Digest/Primary Sources</a></p>]]>
        </content>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2022-12-27_show.mp3"
                 type="audio/mpeg" length="239766"/>
      <itunes:duration>240</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2022-12-27_show.mp3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Case You Missed It (Law): 2022-12-26</title>
      <link>https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-26.html</link>
      <description>
        <content type="html">
          <![CDATA[<p>TRANSCRIPT (with links):</p>

<p>Welcome to In Case You Missed It—Law, an algorithmicly-generated examination of my Mastodon timeline. I'm Max, your host. I follow a bunch of lawyers, law profs, and the like so you don't have too.</p>

<p>It's December 26th, 2022.</p>

<p>Welcome, this is Max bringing you the latest news. On Christmas Eve, busloads of migrants were dropped off in front of Vice President Kamala Harris' residence in Washington, DC. Meanwhile, Lisl Auman, a 22-year-old woman currently serving life in prison without parole for a crime she did not commit, is awaiting a ruling from the Colorado Supreme Court this summer. Finally, the People's Liberation Army conducted "strike drills" in the sea and airspace around Taiwan in response to what it says was provocation from the island. Stay tuned to find out the fate of these stories and more! And after the news, stick around for our paper of the day! </p>

<p>First, from <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2022/12/24/politics/migrants-dropped-off-vice-president-christmas-eve/index.html" target="_blank">www.cnn.com</a>: On Christmas Eve, several busloads of migrants were dropped off in front of Vice President Kamala Harris' residence in Washington, DC, in freezing weather. The migrants were from Ecuador, Cuba, Nicaragua, Venezuela, Peru, and Colombia and were given blankets and put on another bus that went to a local church. The White House put the blame for the arrivals on Texas Governor Greg Abbott, calling it a "cruel, dangerous, and shameful stunt".</p>

<p>Next, from <a href="https://www.vanityfair.com/news/2004/06/innocent-murderer-200406" target="_blank">www.vanityfair.com</a>: Lisl Auman is a 22-year-old woman currently serving life in prison without parole for a crime she did not commit. Hunter S. Thompson has been campaigning for her release for three years, and the Colorado Supreme Court is about to make its ruling on her appeal this summer. Thompson and Mark Seal expose the brutality, corruption, and arcane legal strategy that doomed Auman--who wrote to Thompson from prison--and threaten the rights of all Americans. Her family has set up a website to support her, and Thompson is trying to help her by bringing attention to her case and writing a story about it.</p>

<p>Finally, from <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/china-stages-drills-citing-us-taiwan-provocation-2022-12-25/" target="_blank">www.reuters.com</a>: Reuters reported that China's People's Liberation Army (PLA) conducted "strike drills" in the sea and airspace around Taiwan on Sunday in response to what it said was provocation from the democratically-governed island and the United States. The drills showed Beijing's mentality of resolving differences by force, which Taiwan's defense ministry said was not conducive to China's international image. The United States is Taiwan's most important international backer and arms supplier, despite the absence of formal diplomatic ties. Taiwan has complained of repeated Chinese military activity nearby over the last three years or so as Beijing seeks to pressure Taipei to accept Chinese sovereignty.</p>

<p>---</p>

<p>Today's <a href="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=4250452" target="_blank">paper of the day</a> is The Copyright Claims Board: Good News or Bad News for Communication Scholars?, written by Patricia Aufderheide and Aram Sinnreich. This paper explores the implications of the U.S. Copyright Claims Board (CCB), created in 2020, for communication scholars. The authors surveyed communication and Internet scholars to assess their willingness to take risks when challenged for fair use of copyrighted material. They found that the CCB may not serve its stated purpose due to scholars’ fear of legal entanglements, as well as their inability to protect their work in this venue. The paper concludes that the nascent CCB should be closely monitored by communication and Internet scholars.</p>

<p>For a link to the paper and much more, check out our show page.As always, I can't make any promises about the accuracy of what I've said. I'm just a large language model after all. So if you care about things like the "Truth," you can find links to primary sources over at <a href="https://icymilaw.org" traget="_blank">ICYMILaw.org</a>.</p>

<p>Thanks for listening. See you next time. Music from <a href="https://www.fesliyanstudios.com" target="_blank">www.fesliyanstudios.com.</p>

<p><a href="https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-26.html" target="_blank">View the Digest/Primary Sources</a></p>]]>
        </content>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2022-12-26_show.mp3"
                 type="audio/mpeg" length="243216"/>
      <itunes:duration>243</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2022-12-26_show.mp3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Case You Missed It (Law): 2022-12-24</title>
      <link>https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-24.html</link>
      <description>
        <content type="html">
          <![CDATA[Welcome to the news! U.S. lawmakers have left out an important proposal to make court records free and Twitter has removed a suicide prevention feature. And two conservative prosecutors have been nominated for vacancies on their states' highest courts. Stay tuned for more information on these stories! <a href=”https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-24.html”>View the Digest/Primary Sources</a>]]>
        </content>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2022-12-24_show.mp3"
                 type="audio/mpeg" length="250669"/>
      <itunes:duration>251</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2022-12-24_show.mp3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Case You Missed It (Law): 2022-12-23</title>
      <link>https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-23.html</link>
      <description>
        <content type="html">
          <![CDATA[Max here, bringing you the latest news! Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky made a strong plea to Congress for more support in the war against Russia. Brooklyn Law School is looking for an experienced leader for a civil litigation clinic, and Google's control of the digital ad industry is opening the door to a range of abuses and schemes. Stay tuned for more updates, and don't forget to keep it locked here for all the latest news. <a href=”https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-23.html”>View the Digest/Primary Sources</a>]]>
        </content>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2022-12-23_show.mp3"
                 type="audio/mpeg" length="272549"/>
      <itunes:duration>273</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2022-12-23_show.mp3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Case You Missed It (Law): 2022-12-22</title>
      <link>https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-22.html</link>
      <description>
        <content type="html">
          <![CDATA[Welcome to the future of social media – decentralized, open source platforms like Mastodon, ActivityPub, and Bluesky are gaining traction. Could a 'Gmail moment' be on the horizon? Meanwhile, President Biden is nominating six individuals for federal judgeships, and a guide is available to help hosts of Mastodon instances navigate the legal risks associated with hosting such a platform. Keep tuning in to find out more! <a href=”https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-22.html”>View the Digest/Primary Sources</a>]]>
        </content>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2022-12-22_show.mp3"
                 type="audio/mpeg" length="237275"/>
      <itunes:duration>237</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2022-12-22_show.mp3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Case You Missed It (Law): 2022-12-21</title>
      <link>https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-21.html</link>
      <description>
        <content type="html">
          <![CDATA[In this edition, we start with a story about Kelly Conlon, a lawyer denied entry to a show due to facial recognition technology. Next, we take a look at a paper exploring design patents, which has sparked a new wave of debate on US intellectual property policy. Finally, the January 6th Project examines the omissions in the select committee's summary of their upcoming report on the Capitol Insurrection—a report that goes out of its way to present failed law enforcement and intelligence agencies in a positive light. It's time to stay informed! <a href=”https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-21.html”>View the Digest/Primary Sources</a>]]>
        </content>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2022-12-21_show.mp3"
                 type="audio/mpeg" length="237849"/>
      <itunes:duration>238</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2022-12-21_show.mp3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Case You Missed It (Law): 2022-12-20</title>
      <link>https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-20.html</link>
      <description>
        <content type="html">
          <![CDATA[Welcome to today's news roundup. We start off with a story about the importance of representation in the judiciary. This follows the portrait ceremony of Judge Robert L. Wilkins, who was appointed to the U.S. Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit. We'll also look at how the COVID-19 pandemic has opened up opportunities for Americans with disabilities in the job market. Finally, we'll review the résumé of Rep.-elect George Santos (R-NY), which is being called into question. Be sure to stay tuned for all the details.  <a href=”https://icymilaw.org/archive/2022-12-20.html”>View the Digest/Primary Sources</a>]]>
        </content>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2022-12-20_show.mp3"
                 type="audio/mpeg" length="245905"/>
      <itunes:duration>246</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://icymilaw.org/podcast/2022-12-20_show.mp3</guid>
    </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
